# AHMAD AL-AHMAD

## **Personal Information:**

**Address:** Farnborough, Hampshire

Mobile Number: +44 7763240867

Email Address: ahmad.younes.2005@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-al-ahmad-b54885149

## Profile:

I am a hard-working, quick-learner, and highly-motivated individual with excellent communication skills and more than 8 years experience in IT Desktop Support. I am able to work in a team or individually depending on the task. I am a sociable, friendly, organised and reliable person to work with and ambitious to learn about new technologies.

#### **Qualifications:**

- Gained CompTIA A+ Certificate.
- In addition to my current role, I am pursuing my ambition to learn and gain professional qualifications in web design and web development. I gained:
  - MTA (98-383): Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS Certificate.
  - MTA (98-375): HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals Certificate.
  - MTA (98-382): Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript Certificate.
- Preparing for the following exams:
  - CIW (Certified Internet Web Professional): Advanced HTML5 and CSS3 Specialist.
  - CIW (Certified Internet Web Professional): JavaScript Specialist.
  - MCSA: Web Applications leading towards MCSD: App Builder.

#### **Work Experience:**

#### 8/01/2018 - Present

#### ICT Technician, Yateley School, UK:

Yateley School is the largest secondary school in North East Hampshire. The school teaches over 1500 students aged 11 – 16, and the attached sixth form college caters for ages 16–18.

#### Responsibilities:

- Designing email signature using HTML5.
- Provide first level software and hardware support to users (Teachers, School Staff and Students).
- Using and learning a new help desk software called Spiceworks.
- Install, modify, and repair computer hardware and software and install computer peripherals.
- Using Bradfords Network Network Sentry software to allow users to connect wirelessly to the internet.
- Microsoft Windows and Office activation using VAMT (Volume Activation Management Tool).
- Imaging and re-imaging desktops and laptops using WDS (Windows Deployment Service).
- Creating users and email accounts using Active Directory and Microsoft Exchange Server 2013.
- Mail box size increase using Microsoft Exchange Server 2013.
- Anti-Spam and Web filtering using Smoothwall software.

## 17/10/2017 - 06/01/2018

## Sales Associate (Part Time – Temporary), TKMaxx, UK:

TK Maxx is a subsidiary of the American apparel and home goods company TJX Companies based in Framingham, Massachusetts. TK Maxx stores are operated throughout the United Kingdom, Australia, Ireland, Germany, Poland, Austria and the Netherlands, totalling 515 stores in Europe.

# Responsibilities:

- Work on store sales floors performing various merchandising functions and providing quality customer service.
- Greeting customers, stocking items on racks and shelves, processing customer purchases at cashier stations, and helping shoppers locate merchandise.
- Clean the store and oversee fitting rooms where applicable.

#### 14/11/2011 - 04/02/2016

#### IT Technician, Civil Aviation Authority, Qatar:

The Civil Aviation Authority of Qatar (QCAA) is the government agency responsible for licensing, monitoring, and regulating civil aviation matters. It is administered by the Qatar Ministry of Transport and Communications.

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed and developed intranet website for the company using web programming languages such as HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, MySQL, and PHP.
- Knowledge of Anti-Viruses and perform scanning for malicious Viruses and treating infected computer systems.
- Troubleshooting, configuring, and installing of Microsoft products (Windows 7/8/8.1/10 and Office Suite) and other popular software products on desktops and laptops.
- Configure, install and set up network printers, shared printers and peripheral devices.
- Familiar with LAN structure as I am able to solve and troubleshoot technical network connectivity and dealing with users issues.
- Troubleshoot and resolve basic issues with voice communications (VoIP Telephones such as CISCO phones) and mobile phones.
- Coordinate with vendors or technicians for service and support.
- Providing technical assistance and support for incoming queries and issues relating to computer systems, software, and hardware.

Education: 2001 – 2006, Philadelphia University, Jordan: BSc in Computer Engineering. (GPA 71.5%)

# Skills:

# **Languages:**

- English Fluent.
- Arabic Native.

# **Key Skills:**

- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal.
- Strong troubleshooting skills.
- Microsoft Windows and Microsoft Office.
- HTML, HTML5,
- CSS, CSS3.
- SASS.
- JavaScript.
- MySQL.
- PHP.
- Active Directory and Group Policy.
- Web hosting and domain registration.
- Adobe Photoshop.
- Adobe Dreamweaver.